Never forget why you are the church.
Aren't you glad God is who he is, church?
Amen.
This morning we continue.
Go ahead and turn your Bibles to Romans chapter 8.
We are going to officially finish this great chapter.
And if you remember, we are looking at Paul asking questions
and answering those same questions in
order to persuade us of our position and
provision in God.
Now, I want to remind you, this is not a sales tactic, but rather a declaration.
We talked about, you know, vacuum salesman
last week, and we're all familiar with the dreaded sales tactics of this world.
What you may not know about me at one time.
Has anyone ever heard of anything called vector marketing?
Teenagers.
You ever heard of vector marketing, trying to recruit you?
Okay, there we go.
All right, so back when I went to high school, you'd always get letters
and emails and all the things, and they were trying to get
you to come work for them and what they would do.
You didn't know what vector marketing was, but what it was, is you would sell knives, okay?
Very nice brand of knives, and it
was literally just cold calling, going off references and all the things.
So I was like, You know what?
Hey, that sounds good.
That sounds like sales.
I'll do that for a little bit.
And so I became a door to door, knive salesman.
And, uh, I mean, straight up legit.
And so anyway, so, man, you know, they're training us and doing all these things.
They give us, like, this pack of knives and these scissors, they can cut through pennies.
And literally, I actually found my little pack that I had,
and I don't know if I can say it's not, but we, you
know, a bunch of cut pennies.
Anyway, I don't know if that's illegal.
I hope it's not.
But anyway, that's up to, you know, Vector, not me.
But anyway, but I would go and, man, I would love it.
I mean, I actually enjoyed the job, and I enjoyed
going out on a day of sales and coming back.
They brought us to conferences, and, of course, you know, the conferences, the people that really made it.
Like, they're millionaires.
They telling you, like,
Hey, go sell knives, and they're getting everyone hype.
taking my knives and running to the houses, you know what I'm saying?
And it's just, like, exciting.
Well, man, I went to this one, I went
to this one house to sell some knives.
And it was off of reference, but the way that I got the sales
call was, listen, you don't have to buy anything, I just, I make
15 bucks for every time you let me come in and do my thing.
And so, like, back then, I'm thinking, like, man, I'm rolling that dough, you know what I'm saying?
So I go into the house and out of the gate.
Now, of course, you know, you got your system, you got your play and all the things, and
out of the gate, this guy tells me, he says, I want you to go look at my kitchen,
what is it called?
It's called a counter.
Kitchen counter.
And I said, Okay, so I kind of, like, stepped in,
I looked at the counter, and he had, like, five or six sets of knives.
And I'm like, All right, all right.
And said, I just want you to know that I'm a knife guy.
And, uh, I'm not buying any of your knives because I got the best knives.
And I'm like, okay, so instantly, I'm thinking, what do I do?
Like, I'm, you know, yeah, the 15 bucks is cool, but man, if he buys a bunch of nice, it's expensive.
Nice, like a commissioner.
All the things a salesman thinks about.
And so I'm like, you know what?
Okay, so I start doing my thing and stuff, and then I realize this guy is legit.
He's like, I'm not buying any of your knives.
So I'm like over here using the sieves and everything, just feeling kind
of like silly being there, you know, in the room.
I had to get through the whole thing or I don't get, you know, because he has to fill out a little thing and stuff.
And then I said, I had an epiphany.
I said, listen here, brother, okay?
I want you to go get the best knives
from your best set of knives and bring them in here.
He said, you sure about that?
I said, oh, yeah.
And inside, I'm like, I hope this works.
And so, man, he goes and gets some, and man, you can tell he's proud of him, dude.
I'm talking like he,
I mean, he I mean, they're sharpened.
He literally said, he said, before you got here, you know, I sharpen.
I wanted to make sure you knew that I was the guy and stuff.
And like, okay, well, I'm the guy here.
And so I said, man, this thing right here has a double D edge.
I started doing all the sales pitching and stuff.
And so what I did is, I said, listen, all the things that my knives can do.
I want you to try them with your knives.
So I had a big old rope about that big around and stuff, and I was, man, I, you know what I'm saying?
It just cut straight through.
I said, I tossed on the rope.
said, cut it, man.
He's over here.
And I'm sitting there just getting like, I'm sorry to see that, man.
And so I'm doing my thing and I'm trying to be kind.
I said, okay, now listen, I know you told me you weren't going to buy no knives.
But it's obvious, whoever sold you those past knives, got you.
Because these knives are obviously better.
I said, so what would you like to do?
I want you to know I sold him, like, an $800 set of knowledge.
Amen, you know what I'm saying?
Adam.
But either way, listen, that was some good commission, too.
But either way, right, listen, hey, that
dude was persuaded.
He was convinced that everything I
thought was best for me in terms of knives,
I don't know if you're missing what I'm trying to say here to set up this text or not.
But everything that I thought was good, everything that I thought was right,
man, I have been, it has been revealed to me that there's
something better.
And today I ask you the same question.
Are you persuaded?
This is much more than kitchen knives or any kind of product the world can offer.
This is literally hear me, church.
This is literally life or death.
We went over two of the five questions last week that Paul asked.
question number one.
We see in Romans 8, verse 31.
It says, what shall we then say to these things?
If God before us, who can be against us?
The answer is simple.
I'm not going to spot this like I did last week, but nothing and
nobody is the answer.
Isaiah declares this truth in Isaiah 44, verse
6, thus saith the Lord, the king of Israel, and his redeemer, the Lord of hosts.
I am the first, and I am the last.
And beside me, there is no God.
There is no one above him.
There is no one like him.
There is no one greater than God, period.
He is omnipotent, the all powerful one.
Somebody say amen to that.
This should comfort us in times of good times
and in times of troubled times.
I like how Jesus explains it.
John 10, verse 28 through 30 says, and I give
unto them eternal life, and they shall never perish.
Neither shall any man pluck them out of my hand.
My father, which gave them me, is greater than all, and no
man is able to pluck them out of my father's hen.
I, and my father are one.
Praise the Lord, for that promise.
No one can be against us if God is for us.
Then we see question number 2 in Romans 8.32.
It says this, he does spare not his own son, but
delivered him up for us all.
How shall he not with him also freely, give us all things.
Now we camped out quite a bit here last week.
Now, these 1st 2 questions are rhetorical in nature.
If God did not withhold his own son from us,
he will not withhold all the spiritual blessings we need to
live our life for him.
And in case you missed last week's message.
I want to inform you of one thing.
Some people can look at this and they they put that all
as in all the things they want and all these possessions in
the world and the big house and the nice promotion
and all the nice clothes, right?
And listen, we bought, it's going to get cold, by the way, tonight.
Did y'all see that?
It's like, what are we going to wake up to, like 25 degrees?
That's insanity.
Anyway, so so we were, you know, me and my wife were prepping.
And we bought River
and Ridley, we bought them some winter coats.
And man, we went to Northface to do that.
Now, listen, growing up, I had no North Face.
You know what I'm saying?
that may not be fancy to you, maybe you've made it that way.
We were like, Man, this is really cool.
They're gonna think they're cool.
They gonna look all trendy.
And so we sit there, and last night, we were like,
Hey, we got you something in store.
And they're like,
Hey, show me, show me.
I'll have you know.
We took out them north faces.
You know what my daughters did?
Ah, that's cool.
I was like, what?
I was like, I still haven't got one of these, and you got one.
You're five years old.
Anyway, but listen, all I'm trying to say is this.
The awe is not a North Face.
It's not a nice car.
It's not the things that the world can offer.
Preachers will tell you, oh, when you give your life to Christ,
he desires to have all you want and everything else.
Let me just tell you something.
Sometimes the things we want can get us in trouble.
How many people want so much stuff?
So instead of dedicating their life to the Lord, they dedicate their life to
the job, they dedicate their life to the grind, they dedicate their
life to money, and before you know it, they're in trouble, right?
So, no, the all here that God does not withhold from us.
It is spiritual blessings.
It is everything that pertaineth to being able to
live this life in godliness.
So, we see here that he did not withhold his son.
Therefore, he's not going to withhold all the spiritual blessings we need to live for him.
We're going to jump right into question 3 this morning.
Romans 8, Romans 8, verse 33 says this.
Who shall lay anything to the charge of God's elect?
It is God that justifieth.
Let's pray.
Father, I thank you, Lord, for this morning.
God, I pray that you can just open my mouth clearly, God.
And Lord, I pray that those that have ears to hear, may they hear.
God, again, we thank you.
We love you, in Jesus name, pray.
Amen.
Now this question and the next one have legal
undertones to them.
Again, let's make sure that we understand how the believer in Rome
would have received this question.
Could a Roman emperor bring charges that is
accusations on a believer for worshiping King
Jesus rather than worshiping Caesar or honoring Caesar?
Now, the answer is not what we want to hear.
Yes, he absolutely could charge a Christian
in that time for doing that.
That's why in the early state of the church,
it was so strong because, man, you didn't just show up to church.
You had to be the church.
It wasn't just something like, oh, we have this nice building and
we have the AC and the warm when it gets cold and we have these comfortable
pews and all this stuff.
No, if you were a Christian, you understood that if somebody found
out that I was a Christian, if somebody realized that I didn't worship
these false gods that I didn't worship Caesar, but I worshiped Jesus
of Nazareth, listen, you could literally lose your life.
We are so comforted here in all
the wrong ways as a church.
We think that just because we get a sore toe in the morning, oh, I'm persecuted.
No, that's not persecution.
These believers in Rome understood what this meant.
Now listen, just because Caesar could bring an accusation.
Here's the thing, it would have no effect in the eyes of God.
See, understand it, the president of the United States made it illegal to gather
together and worship the Lord.
Could they toss us in jail for doing so?
Yes they could.
As a matter of fact, our brothers and sisters around
this globe are experiencing that as we speak in some areas.
Yet those charges would have no effect in the eyes of God.
Now, I don't want you to hear what I'm not saying.
That don't mean that we just go around breaking alone in the name of Jesus.
Don't you love how people pick one thing in scripture and don't look at the other things in scripture?
Man, I can't stand that.
Listen, if you want to have a debate with me, read your Bible.
Y'all with me?
Don't be coming just one verse, one chapter, one book.
The Bible also tells us to obey the laws of land.
But what we're seeing here is if
the laws of the land, if we are told by
law, you have to worship something else that you cannot
gather, you cannot obey the word of God, let
me just tell you something, we have a decision to make.
And the only right decision.
is to continue to worship and obey the word of God.
Amen?
Or worship the Lord.
But again, right now, the devil is accusing
the brethren.
We see this in Revelation chapter 12, verse 7 through 10.
It says this.
And there was a war in heaven.
Michael and his angels fought against the dragon and the dragon
fought against his angels and prevailed not.
Neither was there a place found any more in heaven, and a great
dragon was cast out, that old serpent called a devil and Satan,
which deceiveth the whole world.
He was cast down into the earth, and angels
were cast out with him, and I heard a loud voice saying, in heaven, now has
come salvation, and strength, and the kingdom of our God,
and the power of his Christ, for the accuser
of the brethren is cast down, which accused them
before our God, day and night.
The question is, what could the devil be accusing us of?
Well, see, he tries to discredit our faithfulness to God.
He brings our sin back up against us.
Church, the enemy's greatest tactic against believers is
guilt and shame.
If he can keep us worried about our past,
then he can keep us from doing what God wants us to do today.
I cannot tell you how many people refuse
to come to Jesus because they have just done too much.
Or how many believers don't fully surrender their time and their
talent and their treasures because of, well,
preacher, you don't know what I've done.
Church, that's crippling.
That is that is gonna freeze you where you are.
and not gonna allow you to go further than where you are.
Me and my wife have a rule that we try to stick to.
Any of y'all have rules in your marriage?
No?
Well, okay.
I know what my next series is gonna be.
But me and my wife have a very simple, silly rule, and it's really not
silly, 'cause it does help us, but this is not a direct chapter in verse.
I don't get all righteous on us about this.
It's just what me and Heather do, okay?
If it happened more than three days ago,
It's time to get over it.
Amen.
I mean, genuinely, like, that happened early in our, because what we
would do is, we started arguing about all the things that had happened, like,
two weeks ago, and three weeks ago, and, man, we're just letting resentment and
bitterness and anger and wrath and mouse, and all these things that God says to stay away
from, build up in our life, in our marriage, and so we just
finally started telling each other,
Hey, when did that happen?
When did I do this against you?
It was like last week, well, it doesn't matter.
That was more than three days ago.
Now, let me just tell you something.
If it's within that three day period, let me just say, we're gonna argue about it, amen?
But here's the thing.
Does it work out like that all the time?
Obviously not.
Of course not.
But here's the thing, it should.
What about God, though?
I mean, if the accusations, what if
the accusations, that the devil brings forth to him are true.
By the way, often they could be.
We fall in sin all the time.
Listen, we step back in our faithfulness to God all the time.
In my opinion, we make these accusations and we make the job
of the enemy accusing us.
sometimes we make it way too easy.
All he has to do is just kind of relay to God what is happening, and now I get it.
God knows he's all sovereign.
understand that.
But understand what a text is saying.
What if the accusations the devil brings forth are
true?
Well, look at the next verse in Revelations 12, verse 11?
And they overcame him.
By the blood of the lamb, and by the word of their testimony,
and they love not their lives unto the death.
Do you realize who you are?
Do you realize what God has done for you?
And in case you have not real.
In case you're still stuck in that guilt and shame.
In case you're still stuck in that past that had you bound up?
Listen, I know my church family.
I've talked with my church family.
There are people here, even today, that struggle with what they used to
be and what they used to do.
Let me share with you, Colossians chapter 2.
listen, it should excite you right here.
For in him, all the fullness of deity dwells in bodily form.
And in him, you have been made complete.
And he is the head over all rule and authority.
And in him, you were also circumcised with a circumcision,
made without hands in the removal of the body, the flesh, by
the circumcision of Christ, that's talking about our heart, having been
buried with him in baptism.
We just saw that.
In which you were also raised up with him through faith
in the working of God, who raised them in the dead.
Now, this right here is where it gets good.
When you were dead in your transgressions and
the uncircumcision of your flesh, he made you alive together
with him, having forgiven us
all of our transgressions, having canceled
out the certificate of debt, consisting of decrees against
us, which was hostile to us, and he has taken
it out of the way, having nailed it to the cross.
That's what he's done for you.
Amen.
Listen, we don't have to live in that guilt and shame.
He's down to the cross.
Somebody say, thank you, God.
Listen, I have to remind myself of this.
The enemy can bring all the charges he desires against us.
We are covered by the blood of Jesus.
Romans 833.
Who shall lay anything to the charge of God's elect?
It is God that justifieth.
God declares us righteous in his eyes.
That brings us to question four.
Again, there's legal undertones here.
Who is he that condemneth?
It is Christ that dieth, yea, rather that is risen again,
who is even at the right hand of God, who also maketh intercession for us.
You know, we live in a society that loves to bring up
the concept of judgment.
We love it.
We see both sides of the extremes with this.
Either A, we hear the statement of don't judge me.
Who's ever been told that by somebody.
Don't judge me.
People love to tell Christians that because a Christian tries to go to a brother or
sister or someone they love and say, listen, hey, you're not living the right way.
You're not going the right way.
This is not going to do anything good in your life.
You know what they're saying?
You're not my judge.
Don't judge me.
You know what?
That breaks my heart.
That used to infuriate me.
But now it breaks my heart because their mind, their
mindset is not on God's word.
It's on trying to ignore accountability for
sin, trying to ignore the coming condemnation
if they don't know Jesus.
So we see, hey, don't judge me or be, we see people
judging out of a legalistic and unforgiving heart.
When we judge in such a way what we do is we bring condemnation to someone else.
You know, I get to thinking about the woman found in adultery.
You know, by law, listen, by law, every
single person there had every right to pick up a stone, throw
it as hard as they could at this young lady and kill her.
They could have walked away like this right here.
We just upheld the law.
But Jesus stepped in.
Are y'all women this morning?
But Jesus stepped in, and what did he do?
He said that, hey, the 1st one, if any of you
don't have any sin, I'm paraphrasing here.
But if you can if you can cast that stone, and if
you can do so, sinless imperfection, hey, do so.
You know what they started doing?
Dropping the stones.
Why?
Because listen, when we judge out of a legalistic and unforgiving
heart, we better turn that mirror towards ourselves.
We forget so often what God has brought us from.
We forget so often the grace that God has bestowed upon our life.
We forget so often the forgiveness and the mercy that we need.
You know, listen, has anyone ever obtained mercy from God?
You know, the innocent doesn't need mercy?
Only the guilty need mercy.
So if you have obtained mercy, that means you are guilty.
Because mercy is not getting what you deserve.
You with me.
So right here, listen, both can be found inside and outside the church.
Right?
But both do not please God.
See, Paul asked the question, who is who is he that condemneth?
This is directly attached to question three.
In other words, if no charge can be brought against the elect.
God's elect, and no condemnation can be sentenced as well.
This is exactly how Paul began the chapter in verses one and two.
It says this.
There is therefore now no condemnation to them which are in Christ Jesus.
who walked not after the flesh, but after the Spirit, for the law of
the Spirit of life, and Christ Jesus hath made me free from
the law of sin and death.
Now, again, don't hear what the Bible is not speaking.
This does not mean that we get away with patterns of sin or
that sin is tolerated by God.
What it means that in the eyes of God, if
we are believers born again Christians, we have been forgiven
and washed clean.
Anyone have any pet pees?
Okay.
Some of y'all need to get over it.
It happened more than 3 days ago.
If there's a pet peeve of mine,
It is operating while being dirty.
I cannot stand being nasty and sweaty for too long.
I mean, and listen, you know, you say, Pritcher, when do you get sweaty?
Don't be thinking like that.
I do yard work and stuff.
You know what I'm saying?
But how do you fix this?
When you get...
anyone know what I'm talking about, though?
It's just you're nasty.
You feel dirty, you feel gross.
Well, how do you fix this?
I tell you what you don't do.
You don't just keep on doing what you're doing.
That just layers the sweat and filthiness, right?
At some point, it'll get so bad that
it'll begin to affect your work and function.
See, this is how sin operates in our life.
When we allow the accusations of our past, the
devil and the world to distract us from what God has done for us, When
we accept the condemnation that God has taken away from us, It
quickly will cripple our walk with Christ.
And when we stay in that filthiness, listen, it's not just going to affect us.
It's going to affect those around us.
See, some of y'all in your filthiness right now thinking it's no big deal.
It's just my filthiness.
I can do whatever I want preaching.
You know what?
Hey, listen, that's not a good way to live, but if you want to, I can't stop you.
But you know what?
Hey, have you ever smelt someone that stunk?
What do you do?
Ooh.
Whoa.
Well, I mean, think about it.
I mean, seriously, listen, I used to do lawn care, you know what I'm saying?
you know, manual labor and stuff.
And so we were going, man, there's always these
times to where if we were filthy, whatever, we'd get back in the Izuzu,
and then we'd sit there and be like, dude, you stink, bro.
Like, what did you forget your deodorant?
And so what happens?
You try to separate yourself.
And so there's a there's a relational cut because
of the filthiness that you have.
Could you imagine, Anthony, I know you showered up and nice.
But let's pretend like you ain't, you know what I'm saying?
I like, man, Anthony, come get me a hug and embrace it.
Whoa, just kidding, dog.
You staying.
I'm just kidding, you don't, though.
I just playing with you.
He's like, I appreciate you clearing that up.
But it'll have a relational issue with it.
Men here, listen, hey, some of y'all in your filthiness, and you're
wondering why, but this is what you want to say.
Well, my wife don't do what she needs to do.
My wife don't love me the way she's supposed to love me.
My wife don't support me the way she's supposed.
Get out of your filthiness.
You stink.
I hit something there.
Folks, listen, our filthiness and sin will
affect not just our walk, but could very
well, unfortunately, affect those around us.
A little leaven gets the whole love.
Y'all with me this morning, say amen.
So how do you fix it?
You get cleaned up.
First John one.9.
If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and
to cleanse us from all unrighteousness.
First John 2, one and two, my little children, these things write,
I unto you, that ye sin not.
And if any man sin, we have an advocate with the Father, Jesus
Christ the righteous, and he is the propitiation, he's the
covering for our sins, not for ours only, but also for the sins of the whole world.
The enemy cannot undo what God has finished.
But he can try to hinder it.
He can't have your soul, but he could have you today.
He can't have your eternity, but he could have your marriage.
He, listen, he can't, he can't have you forever, but he can have your kids.
We better stay clean, church.
We better get our filthiness.
I like how the Bible knowledge commentary puts it, the
Lord Jesus Christ is indeed the judge, but he is also the one with
whom each believer is identified by faith.
As a result, he is a believer sacrificed for sin,
his new life, his intercessor, and his defense.
Certainly, the judge will not condemn his own who are
in him by faith.
And if that's not enough to comfort you, Paul asked another question.
And we get to the 5th question.
Romans 8.35, we're moving right along, who shall separate us from the love of Christ?
What a question.
There's a line spreading in our world today.
The lie is that there is something or someone that can stop God's love for us.
And I don't know, I know where the lie originated, but I
don't know how churches are fueling that lie or what we're
doing, but more and more people, this is how they think.
Well, God's love only goes this far, feel in the blank.
Well, God loves me, but I did this and he no longer loves me.
Or when I was with the Lord, and then I just had a bad time
in my life, and I got off the path, and now he doesn't love me.
Listen, I need you to understand something.
This is not of God, but rather of the world.
It is a carnal thought because it was conceived out
of carnality.
So let's put that to rest this morning.
Romans 8, 35 through 36.
The question was asked, who shall separate us from the love of Christ.
Shall tribulation?
Or distress, or
famine, or nakedness, or peril, or sword.
As it is written, for thy sake, we are killed all the day long.
We are accounted as sheep for the slaughter.
If we are honest, Paul is not necessarily doing a good job of comforting us with this description.
Think about it.
lets look at what he just said.
Tribulation.
This is trouble or oppression that causes pressure in the life of a believer.
Has anyone felt pressure in your life?
As tribulation?
Distress, that is hardship and difficulties.
Anyone ever been through a heart, a difficult time in their life?
Persecution.
This is speaking on harassment from outside influence.
We've experienced that famine, hunger, and prolonged lack of
food, nakedness, lack of clothing and provision, peril,
danger, sword, a physical emblem of physical conflict.
I want you to notice something that can bring one to shudder at the thought.
Paul is not saying these things won't happen.
Most of the believers hearing this letter in real time would
have experienced most, if not all these hardships at
the moment they're hearing it.
Paul himself was no stranger to tragedy and difficult circumstance.
In speaking on a difference of mindset and situation,
look what he tells the puffed up Corinthians Church in 1st
Corinthians 10 or 4 verse 10 through 14.
We are fools for Christ's sake, but ye are wise in Christ.
We are weak, but you are strong.
You are honorable, we are despised.
Even unto this present hour, we both hungered and thirst and
are naked and are buffeted.
That literally means to be beaten up and have no certain dwelling place.
And labor working with our own hands being reviled.
We bless being persecuted, we suffer it, being defamed,
we entreat, we are made as the filth of the world, and
are the offspring of all things unto this day.
I write not these things to shame you, but as
my beloved sons, I warn you.
Church, if we set our minds and actions to that of a
godly life, all these things will come to pass in some form.
May I remind you of Paul's words to Timothy 2nd Timothy
chapter 3, verse 12, yea, and all that will live godly in Christ.
Jesus shall suffer persecution.
Paul then gives even more description to this.
Verse 36, as it is written, for thy sake, we are killed all the day long.
We were accounting as sheep for the slaughter.
Paul here is quoting Psalm 4412, but she
might be asking, where in the world is the victory here?
I mean, we've asked the question.
But then we get this big list of things that are gonna happen in our life, we desire to live godly.
And then we get compared to sheep being led for the slaughter.
Like, what...
Look at verse 37.
Nay.
And all these things, we are more than conquerors, through
him, that loved us.
Now.
Look at verse 36 again.
Right now, I want you in your Bibles to look at verse 36,
Read it to yourself.
Okay?
All right, taking too long.
Now look at verse 37.
How do we reconcile that?
I mean, think, let's just be, let's just be honest here.
Okay, for thy sake, we were killed all the day long.
We were counting as sheep for the slaughter.
But in all these things, we're more than conquerors, than him that love us.
I like this quote from the new American commentary.
It says this.
The troubles to be faced by the Christian are nothing new.
But have always been the experience of God's people.
At every moment of the day, we face death.
We are considered no better than sheep that are marked for slaughter.
Nevertheless, in all these difficult situations,
We are winning an overwhelming victory through the one who has proven his love for us.
It is a love of Christ that supports and enables the believer
to face adversity and to conquer it.
Christians are not grim stoics who manage to muddle through somehow.
They are victors who have found from experience that God is
ever present in their trials, and that the love of Christ will empower
them to overcome all the obstacles of life.
My question is, are you persuaded of that?
Paul finishes this great chapter with even more emphasis on this
truth of God's love for us.
In verses 38 through 39, for I am persuaded that
neither death nor life, nor angels, nor principalities, nor powers,
nor things to come, nor height, nor death,
nor any other creature shall be able to separate us from the
love of God, which is in Christ, Jesus, our Lord.
Guys, don't lose me here.
We're almost done.
Brothers and sisters, whatever is going on in your life.
Whether it's one or a combination of the things mentioned in verse 35.
You may feel so far from God.
You might be thinking things like, how could God allow this in my life?
Why am I suffering like this?
Or maybe you'd be like David in a psalm.
Maybe he has forsaken me.
I just want to tell you, those are not thoughts.
from God.
Those are deceptions to try to keep you where you are.
When verse 35 asks the question, who shall separate us from the love
of Christ?
The answer is nothing and nobody.
John Chrysostom.
Lived a long, long time ago.
Eventually, Patriarch of the Concinople earned
the moniker golden mouth because of his eloquent sermons against the lavish excesses of his day.
This earned him no favor with Roman authorities.
And when he was brought before the Roman emperor, he was threatened with banishment.
if he remained a Christian.
His reply to the emperor reflects the inside of one who
understands that true freedom in life comes
with freedom and the spirit and security in the love of God.
The back and forth banter was this, thou canst not banish me
for this world as my father's house.
The emperor says, but I will slay thee.
Nay, thou canst not, said a noble champion of the faith, for
my life is hid with Christ.
In God.
I will take away thy treasures.
Nay, but thou canst not for my treasure is in heaven, and my
heart is there.
But I will drive thee away from man, and thou shalt have no friend left.
Nay, thou canst not.
For I have a friend in heaven, from whom thou cannot
separate me.
I defy thee, for there is nothing that
you can do to hurt me.
Do you remember the cut code story?
Well, I just told you what kind of knives it were.
Here's the thing.
To convince the guy who thought he had all the knives he needed, I
asked him to get his best knives from his best set.
He quickly realized, though, that what
I had to offer in that moment was superior to what he thought was best for him.
Don't miss this, church.
almost done.
I want you to think of all the world has to offer you.
Right now.
Young and old, middle aged everybody here.
I want you right now to think, whatever's keeping you, whatever's
maybe got you, just, just, just held on to the world
or whatever you are thinking about trying to hold on to.
I want you to think about what the world has to offer.
Those things that you deem better for you now.
You would never admit it out loud, but your life admits it for you.
Think about them.
Now I want you to simply do this.
I just asked you to get the best of the best the world can offer you.
Now measure it up to the love of God.
Worldly possessions fade and are fleeting.
Worldly ambitions are good for a season.
But the love of God.
For I'm persuaded.
That neither death, nor life, nor angels, nor,
principalities, nor powers, nor
things present, nor things to come, nor height, nor death,
nor any other creature shall be able
to separate us from the love of God, which is in
Christ Jesus, our Lord.
Church this morning, are you persuaded?